<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-05T17:16:25+00:00</updated><id>https://fossrit.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Free and Open Source Software @ RIT</title><subtitle>Center of gravity for Free and Open Source Software at the Rochester Institute of Technology. Learn about open source activities and academia at RIT.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">FOSS Hours</title><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2025/01/16/foss-hours-spring-2025/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FOSS Hours" /><published>2025-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2025/01/16/foss-hours-spring-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2025/01/16/foss-hours-spring-2025/"><![CDATA[<p>Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT!</p>

<p>This is also the home of Office Hours for IGME-582 (Humanitarian Free and Open Source Software Development).</p>

<p>The room is located on the main floor of the SHED (same level as the glass box theater). The room is located on the opposite side of the makerspace from the information desk under the big LED screen.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="meetings-meetups" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT! This is also the home of Office Hours for IGME-582 (Humanitarian Free and Open Source Software Development). The room is located on the main floor of the SHED (same level as the glass box theater). The room is located on the opposite side of the makerspace from the information desk under the big LED screen.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Virtual FOSS Hours</title><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2025/01/09/virtual-foss-hours-jan-15/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtual FOSS Hours" /><published>2025-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2025/01/09/virtual-foss-hours-jan-15</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2025/01/09/virtual-foss-hours-jan-15/"><![CDATA[<p>Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT!</p>

<p>This is the first FOSS hours of the semester and will be held on the GNOME Big Blue Button instance (https://meet.gnome.org/rooms/4ec-joe-vw0-qoy/join)</p>

<p>This is also the home of Office Hours for IGME-582 Humanitarian Free and Open Source Software Development.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="meetings-meetups" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT! This is the first FOSS hours of the semester and will be held on the GNOME Big Blue Button instance (https://meet.gnome.org/rooms/4ec-joe-vw0-qoy/join) This is also the home of Office Hours for IGME-582 Humanitarian Free and Open Source Software Development.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ROAR Day URL Creator</title><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/projects/roarday-url-creator" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ROAR Day URL Creator" /><published>2024-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://fossrit.github.io/projects/roarday-url-creator</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fossrit.github.io/projects/roarday-url-creator"><![CDATA[<p>The ROAR Day URL creator is a small web project built to help ROAR Day ambassadors more easily create donation links to send to their communities during RIT ROAR Day 2024.Prior to the existence of this tool, RIT was using a spreadsheet to store a list of individual links that would automatically pre-fill an organization, department, or club in the ROAR day giving form on the GiveCampus page when clicked. Ambassadors/advocates were then supposed to manually append their unique ID to these URL’s so their advocacy was credited to them.</p>

<p>This URL creator is a simple tool built to essentially automate this process for people to make it far more user-friendly. By pulling the list of organizations from the spreadsheet using the google sheets API, the site is able to allow much faster, easier generation of these URLs.</p>

<p>This project was done in collaboration with, and with the support of Victor Santiago from University Advancement.</p>

<h2 id="future-plans">Future plans</h2>

<p>While there currently aren’t too many plans to expand the project, there does seem to be a strong value potentially extend this project to also help cover other RIT advancement campaigns and fundraising efforts.</p>

<h2 id="resources-and-links">Resources and links</h2>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/MoralCode/AdvancementURLFiller/">GitHub repository</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Adrian Edwards</name></author><category term="projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[TeleIRC bridges communication between Telegram groups and IRC channels. This bot was originally written for the RIT Linux Users Group Telegram group and IRC channel. Today, it is used by communities all over the world.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Final FOSS Hours of the semester</title><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2024/08/23/foss-hours-fall-2024-postthanksgiving/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Final FOSS Hours of the semester" /><published>2024-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2024/08/23/foss-hours-fall-2024-postthanksgiving</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2024/08/23/foss-hours-fall-2024-postthanksgiving/"><![CDATA[<p>Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="meetings-meetups" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FOSS Hours</title><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2024/08/23/foss-hours-fall-2024/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FOSS Hours" /><published>2024-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2024/08/23/foss-hours-fall-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2024/08/23/foss-hours-fall-2024/"><![CDATA[<p>Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="meetings-meetups" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FOSS Hours</title><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2024/02/21/foss-hours-spring-2024/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FOSS Hours" /><published>2024-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2024/02/21/foss-hours-spring-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2024/02/21/foss-hours-spring-2024/"><![CDATA[<p>Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="meetings-meetups" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Work in Academia Summit — Sep 7-9, 2022 in Rochester, NY</title><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/announcements/2022/07/21/open-works-in-academia-summit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Work in Academia Summit — Sep 7-9, 2022 in Rochester, NY" /><published>2022-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://fossrit.github.io/announcements/2022/07/21/open-works-in-academia-summit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fossrit.github.io/announcements/2022/07/21/open-works-in-academia-summit/"><![CDATA[<p>Join us for the <a href="https://www.rit.edu/openworksummit/">first summit regarding Open Work in Academia</a> September 7-9, 2022 in Rochester, NY.</p>

<p>During this summit, attendees will have the opportunity to meet, listen to, and collaborate with some of the leaders in the fields of <a href="https://fossrit.github.io/open-work-definition/">Open Work</a> in Industry, Colleges and Universities and related sectors.</p>

<h2 id="date-and-location">Date and location</h2>

<p>September 7-9, 2022</p>

<p>Hyatt Regency Rochester
125 East Main Street
Rochester, NY, 14604, US</p>

<h2 id="attendee-registration">Attendee registration</h2>

<p>Registration is now open.
The goal of this event is to foster conversations across different areas of specialization and, as a result, we are limiting the registration to 100 attendees.
There’s been significant initial interest in this event since our first announcement and we expect to sell out quickly.
This is planned as an in-person event, COVID-willing, but we’ll move to virtual if we must.</p>

<p><a href="https://apps.ideal-logic.com/ritreg?key=5HCZ-DDY7S_K9KH-5PTF_d45a6151b0e2">Register here</a></p>

<p>For more information about the event, such as the event’s Code of Conduct and details about sponsorship, refer to the main event webpage:</p>

<p><a href="https://www.rit.edu/openworksummit/">https://www.rit.edu/openworksummit/</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Karsten Wade</name></author><category term="announcements" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join us for the first summit regarding Open Work in Academia September 7-9, 2022 in Rochester, NY. During this summit, attendees will have the opportunity to meet, listen to, and collaborate with some of the leaders in the fields of Open Work in Industry, Colleges and Universities and related sectors. Date and location September 7-9, 2022 Hyatt Regency Rochester 125 East Main Street Rochester, NY, 14604, US Attendee registration Registration is now open. The goal of this event is to foster conversations across different areas of specialization and, as a result, we are limiting the registration to 100 attendees. There’s been significant initial interest in this event since our first announcement and we expect to sell out quickly. This is planned as an in-person event, COVID-willing, but we’ll move to virtual if we must. Register here For more information about the event, such as the event’s Code of Conduct and details about sponsorship, refer to the main event webpage: https://www.rit.edu/openworksummit/]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Virtual FOSS Hours</title><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2020/08/27/foss-hours/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtual FOSS Hours" /><published>2020-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2020/08/27/foss-hours</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2020/08/27/foss-hours/"><![CDATA[<p>Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT!
Room password is “<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">foss</code>”.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="meetings-meetups" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT! Room password is “foss”.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RIT Calls for Justice</title><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2020/06/05/calls-for-justice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RIT Calls for Justice" /><published>2020-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2020/06/05/calls-for-justice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2020/06/05/calls-for-justice/"><![CDATA[<p>RIT is hosting an online interfaith vigil titled “Calls for Justice at RIT” at 7 p.m. on Friday, June 5, in response to the killing of George Floyd and the subsequent demonstrations against the systemic racism and police brutality that continue to affect black and brown people across the U.S.</p>

<p>“The purpose of the event is to move the audience toward a feeling of connectedness, provide some level small level of comfort, and give them resources to cope with and respond to the situation,” said Monica Sanford, assistant director for spirituality and religious life and the event’s organizer.
“We acknowledge the situation that is affecting the members of our community so deeply.
We see them and hear them.”</p>

<p>The event will feature remarks from RIT students, faculty, staff and alumni.
Confirmed speakers for the event include:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.rit.edu/directory/mslgsh-michael-laver">Michael Laver</a>, associate dean of the College of Liberal Arts</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.rit.edu/directory/blwnsl-brandon-ruiz-williams">Brandon “BL” Ruiz-Williams</a>, NTID Student Life team coordinator</li>
  <li>SM Huq ’20 (microelectronic engineering), former president of the Muslim Student Association</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.rit.edu/directory/aohsbi-andre-hudson">André Hudson</a>, head of the Thomas H. Gosnell School of Life Sciences</li>
</ul>

<p>The event is open to all members of the RIT community.
To participate in the event, <a href="https://campusgroups.rit.edu/SRL/rsvp_boot?id=714834">register via CampusGroups</a>.
Interpreters have been requested.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="meetings-meetups" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[RIT is hosting an online interfaith vigil titled “Calls for Justice at RIT” at 7 p.m. on Friday, June 5, in response to the killing of George Floyd and the subsequent demonstrations against the systemic racism and police brutality that continue to affect black and brown people across the U.S. “The purpose of the event is to move the audience toward a feeling of connectedness, provide some level small level of comfort, and give them resources to cope with and respond to the situation,” said Monica Sanford, assistant director for spirituality and religious life and the event’s organizer. “We acknowledge the situation that is affecting the members of our community so deeply. We see them and hear them.” The event will feature remarks from RIT students, faculty, staff and alumni. Confirmed speakers for the event include: Michael Laver, associate dean of the College of Liberal Arts Brandon “BL” Ruiz-Williams, NTID Student Life team coordinator SM Huq ’20 (microelectronic engineering), former president of the Muslim Student Association André Hudson, head of the Thomas H. Gosnell School of Life Sciences The event is open to all members of the RIT community. To participate in the event, register via CampusGroups. Interpreters have been requested.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Virtual FOSS Hours</title><link href="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2020/05/07/summer-foss-hours/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtual FOSS Hours" /><published>2020-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2020/05/07/summer-foss-hours</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://fossrit.github.io/meetings-meetups/2020/05/07/summer-foss-hours/"><![CDATA[<p>Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT!
Room password is “<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">foss</code>”.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="meetings-meetups" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Come meet other students and faculty involved with FOSS efforts at RIT! Room password is “foss”.]]></summary></entry></feed>